<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Battle Bots on Battle Bots Documentation</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/</link><description>Recent content in Battle Bots on Battle Bots Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[0001] Use MADR for Architecture Decision Records</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/adrs/0001-use-madr-for-architecture-decision-records/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/adrs/0001-use-madr-for-architecture-decision-records/</guid><description>&lt;!--
ADR Categories:
- strategic: High-level architectural decisions (frameworks, auth strategies, cross-cutting patterns)
- user-journey: Solutions for specific user journey problems (feature implementation approaches)
- api-design: API endpoint design decisions (pagination, filtering, bulk operations)
--&gt;
&lt;h2 id="context-and-problem-statement"&gt;Context and Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the project grows, architectural decisions are made that have long-term impacts on the system&amp;rsquo;s design, maintainability, and scalability. Without a structured way to document these decisions, we risk losing the context and rationale behind important choices, making it difficult for current and future team members to understand why certain approaches were taken.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>[0001] User Registration</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/user-journeys/0001-user-registration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/user-journeys/0001-user-registration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The User Registration journey describes how new users create an account on the Battlebots platform. This is the first step in a user&amp;rsquo;s experience and sets the foundation for their identity, access control, and personalization throughout the platform. A smooth registration process is critical for user acquisition and reduces friction in getting started with battlebots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="user-personas"&gt;User Personas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Persona&lt;/strong&gt;: New Battlebot Developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;: A developer or team looking to deploy and compete with their battlebots in automated competitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quickly create an account to start deploying battlebots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand what access and capabilities they&amp;rsquo;ll have&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel confident their data and bots are secure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid creating yet another username/password combination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pain Points&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Concern about granting OAuth permissions without understanding what data is accessed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unclear terms of service or data usage policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Friction if they need to create a GitHub account first (rare for developer audience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="journey-flow-diagram"&gt;Journey Flow Diagram&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Mermaid syntax to create a flowchart representing the user journey:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Auth0 Login Pages Analysis</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/auth0-login-pages-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/auth0-login-pages-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document analyzes Auth0&amp;rsquo;s login page solutions to determine whether using Auth0 as an authentication provider would be beneficial for the Battle Bots platform instead of implementing custom login pages. Given that Battle Bots plans to use GitHub OAuth for user registration and authentication, this analysis evaluates how Auth0 could serve as an intermediary authentication layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Finding:&lt;/strong&gt; While Auth0 provides robust, secure login solutions with excellent GitHub OAuth integration, it introduces significant complexity and cost for a platform primarily using a single social identity provider (GitHub). For Battle Bots&amp;rsquo; specific use case, direct GitHub OAuth implementation may be more appropriate unless multi-provider authentication or advanced identity management features are anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>OpenFGA Analysis</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/open-source-applications/openfga-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/open-source-applications/openfga-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document analyzes OpenFGA (Open Fine-Grained Authorization), a high-performance authorization system inspired by Google Zanzibar, to determine its suitability for implementing fine-grained access control in the Battle Bots platform. OpenFGA provides Relationship-Based Access Control (ReBAC) that answers authorization questions like &amp;ldquo;Does user U have relation R with object O?&amp;rdquo; rather than traditional role-based approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Finding:&lt;/strong&gt; OpenFGA is a mature, production-ready authorization system that separates authentication from authorization, allowing it to work seamlessly with JWT-based authentication systems. It offers flexible deployment options (Docker, Kubernetes, binary), uses an intuitive DSL for policy definition, and supports dynamic authorization decisions through contextual tuples. For Battle Bots&amp;rsquo; planned GitHub OAuth authentication strategy, OpenFGA provides a robust path to implementing fine-grained permissions for bot management, organization access, and game resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>[0002] User Registration via GitHub OAuth</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/adrs/0002-user-registration-via-github-oauth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/adrs/0002-user-registration-via-github-oauth/</guid><description>&lt;!--
ADR Categories:
- strategic: High-level architectural decisions (frameworks, auth strategies, cross-cutting patterns)
- user-journey: Solutions for specific user journey problems (feature implementation approaches)
- api-design: API endpoint design decisions (pagination, filtering, bulk operations)
--&gt;
&lt;h2 id="context-and-problem-statement"&gt;Context and Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users need a way to register and authenticate with the Battle Bots platform to create and manage their autonomous bots. The registration process should be secure, user-friendly, and minimize friction for developers who are our target audience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keycloak Login Pages Analysis</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/keycloak-login-pages-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/keycloak-login-pages-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document analyzes Keycloak&amp;rsquo;s login page solutions to determine whether using Keycloak as an open-source identity and access management (IAM) provider would be beneficial for the Battle Bots platform instead of implementing custom login pages or using a managed service like Auth0. Given that Battle Bots plans to use GitHub OAuth for user registration and authentication, this analysis evaluates how Keycloak could serve as an authentication layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Finding:&lt;/strong&gt; Keycloak offers a powerful, open-source alternative to managed services like Auth0, providing enterprise-grade authentication features without per-user licensing costs. However, it requires significant operational investment in hosting, maintenance, and security management. For Battle Bots&amp;rsquo; specific use case with a single social identity provider (GitHub), Keycloak introduces substantial infrastructure complexity that may outweigh its benefits during the MVP and early growth phases. &lt;strong&gt;Direct GitHub OAuth implementation is recommended for MVP, with Keycloak as a strategic option only if self-hosted identity management becomes a priority.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>[0003] Stateless Authentication via JWT Tokens</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/adrs/0003-stateless-jwt-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/adrs/0003-stateless-jwt-authentication/</guid><description>&lt;!--
ADR Categories:
- strategic: High-level architectural decisions (frameworks, auth strategies, cross-cutting patterns)
- user-journey: Solutions for specific user journey problems (feature implementation approaches)
- api-design: API endpoint design decisions (pagination, filtering, bulk operations)
--&gt;
&lt;h2 id="context-and-problem-statement"&gt;Context and Problem Statement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After users authenticate via GitHub OAuth (ADR-0002), the platform needs to authenticate subsequent API requests. Traditional session-based authentication stores user state on the server, requiring session lookup on every request and creating horizontal scaling challenges. How should the Battle Bots platform authenticate API requests in a scalable, secure manner without server-side session state?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>