<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Battle Bots Documentation</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Battle Bots Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Auth0 Login Pages Analysis</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/auth0-login-pages-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/auth0-login-pages-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document analyzes Auth0&amp;rsquo;s login page solutions to determine whether using Auth0 as an authentication provider would be beneficial for the Battle Bots platform instead of implementing custom login pages. Given that Battle Bots plans to use GitHub OAuth for user registration and authentication, this analysis evaluates how Auth0 could serve as an intermediary authentication layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Finding:&lt;/strong&gt; While Auth0 provides robust, secure login solutions with excellent GitHub OAuth integration, it introduces significant complexity and cost for a platform primarily using a single social identity provider (GitHub). For Battle Bots&amp;rsquo; specific use case, direct GitHub OAuth implementation may be more appropriate unless multi-provider authentication or advanced identity management features are anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Keycloak Login Pages Analysis</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/keycloak-login-pages-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/security/keycloak-login-pages-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document analyzes Keycloak&amp;rsquo;s login page solutions to determine whether using Keycloak as an open-source identity and access management (IAM) provider would be beneficial for the Battle Bots platform instead of implementing custom login pages or using a managed service like Auth0. Given that Battle Bots plans to use GitHub OAuth for user registration and authentication, this analysis evaluates how Keycloak could serve as an authentication layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Finding:&lt;/strong&gt; Keycloak offers a powerful, open-source alternative to managed services like Auth0, providing enterprise-grade authentication features without per-user licensing costs. However, it requires significant operational investment in hosting, maintenance, and security management. For Battle Bots&amp;rsquo; specific use case with a single social identity provider (GitHub), Keycloak introduces substantial infrastructure complexity that may outweigh its benefits during the MVP and early growth phases. &lt;strong&gt;Direct GitHub OAuth implementation is recommended for MVP, with Keycloak as a strategic option only if self-hosted identity management becomes a priority.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>