<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source Applications on Battle Bots Documentation</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/open-source-applications/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source Applications on Battle Bots Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/open-source-applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OpenFGA Analysis</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/open-source-applications/openfga-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-139/rd/analysis/open-source-applications/openfga-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="executive-summary"&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This document analyzes OpenFGA (Open Fine-Grained Authorization), a high-performance authorization system inspired by Google Zanzibar, to determine its suitability for implementing fine-grained access control in the Battle Bots platform. OpenFGA provides Relationship-Based Access Control (ReBAC) that answers authorization questions like &amp;ldquo;Does user U have relation R with object O?&amp;rdquo; rather than traditional role-based approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Finding:&lt;/strong&gt; OpenFGA is a mature, production-ready authorization system that separates authentication from authorization, allowing it to work seamlessly with JWT-based authentication systems. It offers flexible deployment options (Docker, Kubernetes, binary), uses an intuitive DSL for policy definition, and supports dynamic authorization decisions through contextual tuples. For Battle Bots&amp;rsquo; planned GitHub OAuth authentication strategy, OpenFGA provides a robust path to implementing fine-grained permissions for bot management, organization access, and game resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>