<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Grafana Loki on Battle Bots Documentation</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-153/research_and_development/analysis/observability/logs/loki/</link><description>Recent content in Grafana Loki on Battle Bots Documentation</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-153/research_and_development/analysis/observability/logs/loki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Loki: OTLP Integration</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-153/research_and_development/analysis/observability/logs/loki/loki-otlp-integration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-153/research_and_development/analysis/observability/logs/loki/loki-otlp-integration/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grafana Loki introduced native OpenTelemetry Protocol (OTLP) support in version 3.0, marking a significant advancement in how logs can be ingested into Loki. This native integration allows applications instrumented with OpenTelemetry to send logs directly to Loki using the standardized OTLP format, eliminating the need for format transformations and simplifying the observability pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The native OTLP endpoint provides a fully OpenTelemetry-compliant ingestion path where logs sent in OTLP format are stored directly in Loki without requiring conversion to JSON or logfmt blobs. This approach leverages Loki&amp;rsquo;s structured metadata feature, which stores log attributes and other OpenTelemetry LogRecord fields separately from the log body itself. The result is a more intuitive query experience and better performance, as queries no longer need to parse JSON at runtime to access fields.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Loki: Overview</title><link>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-153/research_and_development/analysis/observability/logs/loki/loki-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://z5labs.github.io/battlebots/pr-preview/pr-153/research_and_development/analysis/observability/logs/loki/loki-overview/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grafana Loki is a horizontally-scalable, highly-available, multi-tenant log aggregation system designed to be cost-effective and easy to operate. Inspired by Prometheus, Loki takes a fundamentally different approach to log storage compared to traditional systems like Elasticsearch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core innovation of Loki is its index-free architecture: instead of indexing the full contents of log lines, Loki only indexes metadata labels for each log stream. This design dramatically reduces storage costs, memory requirements, and operational complexity while still enabling fast queries through label-based filtering and grep-style text search.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>